Guide to the Annie Stein Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Annie Stein Papers,
1954-1993
[Bulk Dates: 1954-1981].
Stein, Annie.
13 linear ft. (31 document boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library New York, NY. 10027
MS#1481
6909494
These papers contain reports, newsletters, newspaper clippings, and statistical analyses related to Annie Stein's career as an activist for integration in the New York City public schools.
Biographical Note
"The average child in eighty-five percent of the Black and Puerto Rican schools is functionally illiterate after eight years of schooling in the richest city in the world. This is a massive accomplishment." These first sentences, from an essay Annie Stein wrote for the Harvard Educational Review in 1971, encapsulate a lifetime of radical activism, a career in statistical research, and a habit of righteous anger.
For nearly 50 years-- working through labor unions, civil rights committees, and community groups-- Stein used these energies to combat the routines and institutions of racism. Her efforts could be structural or personal; she wrote amicus briefs in crucial legal battles, and she rebuked individual vendors on Coney Island for selling Confederate flags. She mobilized to defend the Scottsboro Boys in the 1930s. During the 1940s, she helped lead the movement to integrate restaurants in Washington, D.C. From the 1950s through the 1970s, she struggled to end segregation in New York City's public schools. This was her greatest campaign-- involving thousands of students, parents, teachers, researchers, and administrators-- but it was also her most frustrating one.
In 1954, the U.S. Supreme Court's ruling in Brown v. Board of Education of Topeka denied the legality of "separate but equal" education. With varying degrees of enthusiasm, school districts around the nation considered how to implement the new laws "with all deliberate speed." But, in New York this blandishment hardly seemed necessary. The City-- northern, liberal, wealthy-- was already ahead of schedule. The leaders of its school system had issued their own statement in 1954, and it was even more ambitious than the federal mandate. "It is now the clearly reiterated policy and program of the Board of Education of the City of New York," it read, "to devise and put into operation a plan which will prevent the further development of such [segregated] schools and would integrate the existing ones as quickly as practicable."
That year, the City possessed 52 schools where all the students were either Black or Puerto Rican. Classrooms in neighborhoods such as Harlem and Bedford-Stuyvesant were overcrowded and dysfunctional, while excellent schools in nearby white enclaves operated with hundreds of empty seats. For years, activists worked to fix this imbalance.
Organizing with parents and community groups in the underserved areas, Stein demanded mass transfers, bussing, open enrollment-- anything to get children into the high-grade institutions. The School Board refused to offer more than token concessions. Finding that racist fears were too powerful to allow existing white schools to be segregated, Stein and others agreed that the Board should construct new academies in mixed neighborhoods. Marshaling a huge investment, the City built 244 schools, but 57 percent of them were already completely segregated when their doors first opened for operation. Administrators resorted to every expedient to ensure this. In some instances, zoning lines ran right down the street where the school had been built. Black and Puerto Rican students lived on one side-- they would attend classes in the new building. On the other side of the street, the white side, students were zoned for a different school, often miles away.
In 1964, Stein joined community leaders and thousands of parents to plan a one-day boycott. Mobilizing the tactics of the civil rights movement, the organizers leafleted the city, focusing on "places where women gather-- beauty shops, Laundromats, small groceries," and demanding strict discipline. "In keeping with the dignity of our cause, picket lines should be carried out in a quiet and orderly fashion," their instructions read. "Our appeal to people is a moral one. Under no circumstances should anyone attempt physically to stop a person from entering a school." On Freedom Day, Feb. 3, 1964, half a million students stayed home. It was a dramatic action, but the fundamental problems remained.
Following a decade of policy vacillation, political confrontations, and the investment of billions of dollars, New York found itself with 201 schools that only served Black and Puerto Rican students-- a fourfold increase over 1954. In 860 schools, there were only four Black principals. Integration had failed. The City was forced to issue an embarrassing confession: "We must conclude that nothing undertaken by the New York City Board of Education since 1954 has contributed or will contribute in any meaningful degree to desegregating the public schools of the city."
The parents and communities in suffering neighborhoods changed their strategy. Instead of trying to switch their children into white schools, they attempted to gain autonomy over the segregated institutions that had been foisted on them. They called the new tactic, "community control." But sovereignty over the schools required power over hiring and firing. In Ocean Hill-Brownsville, the community board attempted to terminate several white teachers. The United Federation of Teachers would not allow this. In 1968, for several weeks, 50,000 union teachers and administrators went on a series of strikes. The ensuing conflict degenerated in recriminations and violence. The union played up instances of anti-Semitism and "Black extremist excesses," while community members spoke of racism and Apartheid. The conflict revealed fissures that many liberals had believed were closed. New Yorkers had to choose between their loyalty to labor or to civil rights. Annie Stein had ties to both movements. She had never crossed a picket line in her life. But she did so in Ocean Hill-Brownsville, and without hesitation. Her commitment was to the students and parents of the City.
"Let's shake these learned cobwebs from our eyes and look at the reality," she once wrote. To achieve this, she contributed her energies, research, and critical analysis to such groups as the Brooklyn NAACP, the Public Education Association, and Parents Against Racism in Education. In her articles and polemics, she was apt to cite Kenneth Clark or Franz Fanon, but most of her source material was provided by her opponents. Jammed filing cabinets encroached from the walls in her one-bedroom apartment. Over the years, she filled the drawers with clippings from newspapers and magazines, official school board publications, and research reports. Using these, she distilled the data into devastating accusations against the school system. When liberal educators issued their findings, she was able to refute them with their own evidence. Her rage transferred into columns and rows of pencil-scratched numbers. But, even as she analyzed the minutiae of double-humped curves and numerical "flip points," her work always kept focus on the larger issues. Racism in schools was not a statistical problem. It was not even an educational problem. It was a social problem.
In Stein's opinion, the racial divide in education reflected basic economic relations. "Blacks and Puerto Ricans are needed to man the restaurant kitchens, the hospital orderly jobs, the handtrucks and workrooms of the garment district, the unskilled port jobs, and the draft calls," she wrote. Whites, on the other hand, were "trained to fill the hundreds of thousands of office jobs in this financial and commercial capital of the world."
Failure required everyone to contribute. "It took the effort of 63,000 teachers, thousands more administrators, scholars, and social scientists, and the expenditure of billions of dollars to achieve," Stein wrote. "Alone, however, the 'professional' educators could not have done it. They needed the active support of all the forces of business, real estate interests, trade unions, willing politicians, city officials, the police, and the courts." Teachers expected Black and Puerto Rican students to fail. Sociologists predicted their families to be pathological. Neighborhoods knew that integrated schools would not be able to teach effectively.
Stein challenged the City and its citizens to do better. Educational injustice could only end if prejudice itself was defeated. And this could only occur if the rising generations were raised together in tolerance. "If racism in the society at large becomes reflected in school policies," she concluded in one report, "remedy must be sought through continuing and extending the battle against racism in society as a whole and by protecting the child from this racism. School policies and attitudes cannot be permitted to continue to reflect society's racism."
Annie Stein's work remained unfinished when she died in May 1981. She was 68 years old.
Scope and Content
The Annie Stein Papers contain research materials, newspaper clippings, publications and reports related to the attempts to desegregate New York City's public schools.
Arrangement
The material in the collection has been kept in its original order; an alphabetical list is available.
Subjects
Ocean Hill-Brownsville Demonstration School District (New York, N.Y.); Galamison, Milton A. (Milton Arthur), 1923-1988; Academic achievement--United States.; African Americans--Education.; African Americans--New York (State)--New York--Relations with Jews.; African American students--Attitudes.; Discrimination in education--New York (State)--New York.; Education--Political aspects--New York (State)--New York.; Public schools--New York (State)--New York.; Schools integration--New York (State)--New York--History.; Schools--Centralization--New York (State)--New York.; Schools--Decentralization--New York (State)--New York.; Strikes and lockouts--Teachers--New York (State)--New York.; Teacher-student relationships--United States.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
The RBML received these papers in a transfer from Columbia Teachers College in 2009.
[Provenance]
Finding aid in repository and online; folder level control.
- Files
  - Education Reports, 1970-1984, (3 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 1 to 3)
  - Science Clippings, 1971-1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - School District Analyses, 1981-1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Clippings--1968 School Strike, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Council on Interracial Books, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Articles by Martin Deutsch, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - CRMD, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Summary Tables--Ethnic, 1960-1966 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Articles--NYC Schools, 1968-1974 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Open Admissions and Community Colleges, 1968-1974 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Un Nuevo Dia and other Publications, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - College Action, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - CUNY, 1965-1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Community College, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Rhetoric on Integrated Board of Education, 1954-1971 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Fuchs Shipman Ilich, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Staten Island Community College, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Harlem Parents Committee, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Community District 2, 1967-1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Community District 3, 1970-1977 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Community District 5, 1971-1976 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Community District 6, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Community District 8, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Community District 10, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Community District 11, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Community District 12, 1968-1974 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Community District 13, 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Community District 14, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Community District 15, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Community District 18, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Community District 19, 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Community District 20, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Community Districts 21 and 22, 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Community District 23, 1965-1977 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Community District 28, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Accountability, 1971-1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Brody-Jones et al. vs. Macchiarola et al., 1977-1978, (3 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 2 to 4)
  - Prescription Drugs in Class, 1970-1973 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Reports, 1971-1980 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Pamphlets and Notes, 1971-1978, (2 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 1 to 2)
  - AERA Talk, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Watchdog, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Science and Society article, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - High Schools
    - High School Bronx, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Elite High School, 1971-1977 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Alternative High School and Pushouts, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - High School Critical Studies--Data, 1970-1974 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - High School Data, 1966-1975 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - George Washington H.S. Data, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - High School Protest, 1967-1969 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Washington Irving High School, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Andrew Jackson High School, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - John Jay High School, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - High School Diplomas, 1969-1973 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - High School Finances, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - “Disruption”--High School--Causes and Cures, 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Rights of High School Students, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Vocation High School and Satellite Academies, 1969-1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Hunter College High School, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Harlem Prep, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Benjamin Franklin High School, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Eastern District High School, 1969-1972 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Canarsie High School, 1969-1971 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Boys and Girls High School, 1968-1975 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - High School Local Actions, 1969-1972 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Woodrow Wilson, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - New Utrecht, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - New Park East High School, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Music and Art, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - MLK High School, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - August Martin High School, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Mark Twain High School, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Manhattan High School, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Long Island City High School, 1972-1976 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Francis K. Lane High School, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - New Harlem High School, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - United Parents Association, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - George Wingate High School, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - 110 Livington Street, 1965-1976, (2 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 29 to 30)
  - Robinson Board, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - High School Principals Association, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Community Board Powers, 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Central Board vs. Local Boards, 1970-1973 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - School Board Election Procedures, 1973-1977 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Redistricting, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Canarsie, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Integration Plans--Bronx, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Mixed Districts, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Board of Education, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Data By Schools, 1962-1965, (4 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 1 to 4)
  - Integration Plans--Brooklyn, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Accountability Plan, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Advocacy, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Alternative Schools, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - X Districts, 1971-1978, (7 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 9 to 15)
  - Alternative Education, 1968-1973 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Biblios, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Bilingualism, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Education Park, 1963-1967 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Black Studies, 1963-1966 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Boston Zoning and Busing, 1974-1975, (2 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 3 to 4)
  - Breakfast Program, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Budget Crisis, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - The Bus, 1972-1976 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Regents--State, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Maintenance and Repair, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - NY State Education Department, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Parochial, 1966-1972 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Church-State, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - CSB Elections, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Dropout Hearing, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Community Control--Other Cities, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Curriculum, 1964-1970, (2 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 16 to 17)
  - Curriculum-Promotion, 1969-1972 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Examiners, 1964-1973 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Career Education, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Mexican-Americans and Chicanos, 1967-1975, (3 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 4 to 6)
  - Integration Cases--National, 1970-1976 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Lunch Program, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Legal Action, 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Homework Helper, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Manpower Training, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Paraprofessionals, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Construction--Educational Construction Fund, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - CORE--Independent School District, 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Program Summary--Edythe Babette Edwards, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Think Pieces--Editorials, 1971-1976 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Repression--Crime, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - “Shanker Says,” 1976 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Elections, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Compensatory Education, 1962-1972 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Council Data, 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - District Actions, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Attacks on Decentralization, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Drugs, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Indian, 1970-1977, (2 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 6 to 7)
  - PEA Reports, 1970s (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Articles and Newsletters, 1975-1978 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Clips--WC, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - School Achievement Rankings, 1972-1974, (2 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 11 to 12)
  - School Elections, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - State Urban Education Proposals, 1969-1970, (2 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 14 to 15)
  - State Integration Fund, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Integration Plans--Queens, 1963-1966 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Suspensions, 1967-1972, (2 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 18 to 19)
  - Students’ Rights, 1972-1973, (2 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 20 to 21)
  - Special Schools, 1965-1971 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - “600” Schools, 1964-1969 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Special Education, 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Pupil Promotions--Junior High, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Junior High School 8 Queens, 1966-1968 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Histories, 1966-1974 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Leacock, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Federal Agency Statements, 1964-1972 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Fiscal Crisis, 1975-1977 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Action on School Strike, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Handicapped, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Politicians--Statements on NYC Schools, 1964-1969 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Summary Data, 1957-1959 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Achievement--Junior High School Study, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Achievement Data Study--Elementary, 1958-1959 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Achievement Memo, 1958-1967 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Utilization of Schools Maps, 1958-1960 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Data for PEA Schools, 1954-1960, (2 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 18 to 19)
  - Statistics, 1957-1959 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Brooklyn Data Prior to 1957, 1954-1958 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlets and Reports, 1964-1976, (2 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 3 to 4)
  - Teachers Strike, 1968, (2 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 5 to 6)
  - Right to Education--Draft, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Notes for Autobiographical Cookbook, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Accountability, 1970-1971 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Class Size, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Rudolph--Toward Science, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - MacDonald, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Wastnedge--“Learning” to Teach, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Parents--Newson, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Galanter, Ruth 1993 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Weber--“What is Prime,” 1975 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Weber--“It is Winter,” 1960 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Weber--On Schachtel, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Linear City--History, 1967-1969 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Linear City--Plans, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Clippings and Reports, 1969-1993, (2 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 14 to 15)
  - Brownsville Model Cities, 1969-1973 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - School Board 23, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - History of Spring Creek Education Park, 1963-1969 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Brownsville Education Park, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Fruitless Negotiations, 1964-1965 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Peoples Center for the Arts--Gary, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Title III--Umbrella Program, 1966-1970 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Women--Discrimination in Schools, 1972-1973 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Ethnicity Statistics, 1963-1970 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Growth of Segregation, 1965-1969 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Official Decentralization Plans, 1967-1968 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Rein, Dave 1979 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Views--Harlem Parents Committee, 1966-1967 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Urban League Report--“A Study of the Problems of Integration in New York City Public Schools Since 1955,” 1963 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Racism Reports, 1958-1965 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Schools vs. Community, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Implementation--Allen Place, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Integration Plans--Not New York City, 1955-1964 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Boycott, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Achievement, 1974-1975, (2 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Indianapolis, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Buffalo, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - P.A.T. Boycott, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Boycotts, 1964-1965 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Allen Plan, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Oklahoma City, 1969-1977, (2 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 8 to 9)
  - Reading Scores and Rank, 1977-1978 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Achievement Scores, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Reading Scores, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Rochester, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Philadelphia Title I Suit, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Milwaukee, 1975-1976 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Houston Reading Scores, 1966-1974 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Pontiac Michigan Study, 1973-1974 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Flint Michigan Report, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Early Decentralization Debates, 1960-1965 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Strike Settlement Comment, 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Districting Problems, 1969-1970 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Board Decentralization Plan and Hearings, 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Open Enrollment--Integration--Official Documents, 1968-1970 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Brooklyn Museum, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Teacher Action for Community Control, 1967-1969, (2 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 9 to 10)
  - SCOPE Bulletin, 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - UFT Contract, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - News Clips on Decentralization Debate, 1967-1968 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Short-Range Decentralization, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Bundy Report, 1967-1968 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Reverse Open Enrollment, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Teachers’ Strike, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Unemployment, 1964-1972 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Population Data--NY, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Income, 1970-1972 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Reports and Statistics, 1959-1975 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Community Board Elections Protest, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Training Teachers, 1965-1974 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - NY State Legislature, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 12)